<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Lee Turner</title>
    <link>https://leeturner.me/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Lee Turner</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 10:20:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://leeturner.me/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating Hugo Blog Posts from Meetup Pages using Kotlin Script and JSoup</title>
      <link>https://leeturner.me/post/creating-hugo-blog-posts-from-meetup-pages-using-kotlin-script-and-j-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 10:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leeturner.me/post/creating-hugo-blog-posts-from-meetup-pages-using-kotlin-script-and-j-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dark-side-of-running-a-meetup-group&#34;&gt;The Dark Side of Running a Meetup Group&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy running the &lt;a href=&#34;https://brightonkotlin.com&#34;&gt;Brighton Kotlin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://brightonjug.com&#34;&gt;Brighton JUG&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;meetup groups. It is purely selfish to be honest, I get to meet lots of interesting people and learn a lot from the&#xA;speakers and attendees and generally geek out with like-minded people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, there is a lot of admin involved in running a meetup group, let alone two - especially when you decide to set&#xA;up a dedicated blog for each of the meetup groups. Add that to a full time job and family commitments and it makes an&#xA;interesting juggling act. So, inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/osteel&#34;&gt;Yannick&lt;/a&gt;, one of the organisers of the&#xA;local &lt;a href=&#34;https://phpsussex.uk/&#34;&gt;PHP meetup&lt;/a&gt;, and the way he &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PHPSussex/phpsussex.github.io&#34;&gt;automates&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;the updating of the website homepage, I decided that it was time for me to look at my setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Progression Framework in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://leeturner.me/post/hugo-progression-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 10:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leeturner.me/post/hugo-progression-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to progression frameworks last year when I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/monzo/progression-framework&#34;&gt;Monzo progression framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really like the idea that people within an organisation have a tool to help them grow and hone their strengths along with organisations ensuring they are in good shape, and their employees are happy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Monzo progression framework is built using the Gatsby static site builder which makes the frameworks easy to build and track via source control. I have never used Gatsby, but I do have some investment in the Hugo static site builder, and we also use that at &lt;a href=&#34;https://crunchtech.medium.com/&#34;&gt;Crunch&lt;/a&gt;, so I thought I would see if I could put a hugo template together that can render progression frameworks in the same data format as Monzo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
