<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tdd on Lee Turner</title>
    <link>https://leeturner.me/tags/tdd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tdd on Lee Turner</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 22:09:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://leeturner.me/tags/tdd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Camel Case @DisplayNameGenerator For JUnit 5</title>
      <link>https://leeturner.me/post/building-a-camel-case-junit5-displaynamegenerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 22:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leeturner.me/post/building-a-camel-case-junit5-displaynamegenerator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think it is fair to say that &lt;a href=&#34;https://junit.org&#34;&gt;JUnit&lt;/a&gt; has been my go to unit testing framework for quite a while.  I have used &lt;a href=&#34;https://testng.org/&#34;&gt;TestNG&lt;/a&gt; on some pretty major projects where it was already in use (and it has some awesome features) but if I am building something from scratch, I will most likely reach for the JUnit maven dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was solidified even further with the release of JUnit 5.  I won&amp;rsquo;t go into any detail here of what the major differences are between version 4 and 5 because there are loads of great articles on the web about this already.  However, some of my favourites are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Feedback With TDD &amp; Auto Running Tests</title>
      <link>https://leeturner.me/post/continuous-feedback-with-tdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 22:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leeturner.me/post/continuous-feedback-with-tdd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of my &amp;lsquo;reference&amp;rsquo; posts which pretty much means I am writing about it here so I don&amp;rsquo;t forget about it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post it about configuring your dev environment to provide you with continuous feedback while writing your code.  All of this came about after a conversation with another developer on my team about how to setup IntelliJ to run tests automatically.  We were looking at plugins such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://infinitest.github.io&#34;&gt;Infinitest&lt;/a&gt; but it all seemed a little clunky and crashed every so often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
