<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reference on Lee Turner</title>
    <link>https://leeturner.me/tags/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reference on Lee Turner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 10:20:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leeturner.me/tags/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outputting the result of a mockMvc call</title>
      <link>https://leeturner.me/post/outputting-result-of-mockmvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 10:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeturner.me/post/outputting-result-of-mockmvc/</guid>
      <description>This post falls into the category of something I always forget and need to Google.
When running spring integration tests and using mockMvc, it can often be useful to see the output of the call in the console to help with debugging. This can be done by adding MockMvcResultsHandlers.print() to the call chain like in the following example.
This:
@Test void getStatementsThrowABadRequestWhenCookiesNotPresent() throws Exception { mockMvc.perform(get(&amp;#34;/statements&amp;#34;) .headers(getHeaders()) .cookie(getCookies()) .contentType(MediaType.APPLICATION_JSON)) .andExpect(status().isBadRequest()) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying A Branch Name In Intellij</title>
      <link>https://leeturner.me/post/copying-the-branch-name-in-intellij/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 18:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeturner.me/post/copying-the-branch-name-in-intellij/</guid>
      <description>How many times do you need to use the name of the branch you are currently working on ? Entering the name of the branch into your CI/CD system to deploy your feature branch into a staging environment, sending the name over email or internal messaging app to a co-worker who you are pair-programming with&amp;hellip;
I seem to need to do this quite frequently over the course of a working week, and the place I always go to get the branch name is Intellij.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Feedback With TDD &amp; Auto Running Tests</title>
      <link>https://leeturner.me/post/continuous-feedback-with-tdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 22:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeturner.me/post/continuous-feedback-with-tdd/</guid>
      <description>This is the first of my &amp;lsquo;reference&amp;rsquo; posts which pretty much means I am writing about it here so I don&amp;rsquo;t forget about it in the future.
This post it about configuring your dev environment to provide you with continuous feedback while writing your code. All of this came about after a conversation with another developer on my team about how to setup IntelliJ to run tests automatically. We were looking at plugins such as Infinitest but it all seemed a little clunky and crashed every so often.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
